Kimberly Love

Washington, D.C. | 513-939-6511| kimberlymlove15@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | Blog: <u>Medium</u> | <u>Portfolio Website</u>

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a dedicated and innovative software engineer with experience in frontend, backend, and full stack development. My diverse background in physical therapy and youth athletics brings a unique perspective that enriches my approach to crafting innovative technical solutions. My commitment to continuous education drives my effort to stay knowledgeable about modern technologies, ensuring I can contribute effectively to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Flask, Flask-SQLAlchemy, RESTful APIs, Git, GitHub, SQL, SQLite, ORM, OOP

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

GoodSport - Github | Demo | Live Site (Deployed on Render, can take 1-2 minutes to spin up)

A sports team schedule management app that allows users/players to be added to a team and view all events associated with their team, while coaches can add, update and delete events for their teams.

- Implemented CRUD functionality, enabling account creation, event management, and efficient data manipulation
- Established key relationships among Teams, Coaches, Players, and Events through designing a relational database structure with Flask-SQLAlchemy and SQLite
- Incorporated secure password hashing using bcrypt, enhancing data protection by encrypting user passwords
- Enforced data validation rules for player and user information during creation and updates, ensuring data integrity
- Integrated RESTFUL API routes with Flask and Python for streamlined frontend-backend communication
- Developed an auto-login route if user doesn't deliberately logout using the Session object in Python
- Incorporated client-side routing with React Router to emulate a Multi-Page Application (MPA) experience within a Single-Page Application (SPA)

FitConnect - Github | Demo | Live Site (Deployed on Render, can take 1-2 minutes to spin up)

FitConnect seamlessly blends fitness logging with a social media twist, where users can share workout insights, post reflections on stored routines, and create new shareable workouts for others to engage with and provide feedback on.

- Integrated form validations for Login and Signup forms, utilizing React state management for real-time UI error messages based on user input
- Developed backend user-centric Posts functionality, enabling creation, editing, and deletion of workout-related posts
- Implemented an efficient filter feature in the Posts section, enhancing content exploration for users

FlatStop - Github | Demo

A virtual game store that offers an immersive shopping experience where users can explore, curate and buy/sell their favorite games, all through simple commands.

- Developed a Python-based Command Line Interface (CLI) application, creating an immersive virtual game store
- Enhanced interactivity by incorporating a dynamic bargaining feature for game sales
- Added a login and account creation feature, ensuring a more secure and personalized experience
- Leveraged Python's SQL capabilities to seamlessly map Python classes to a SQLite database to perform CRUD
- Implemented fine-tuned search functionality as a way to filter games based on criteria such as game rating and title

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OrthoVirginia, Physical Therapy Technician - McLean, VA

April 2018 - July 2023

- Managed a 6-person team of technicians and oversaw scheduling, training and daily office operations for the techs
- Assisted the Physical Therapists during patient treatment by providing joint distractions and guided joint mobilizations
- Worked hands-on with patients through therapeutic exercises

DC Soccer Club, Travel Coach - Washington, DC

August 2017 - June 2023

- Coached and trained multiple teams of ages 5-14, while also overseeing all team and administrative operations
- Developed and implemented practice plans that are both instructive and stimulating to promote player development
- Evaluated and assessed player performance to provide individualized reports for player growth and development

Source Physical Therapy and Wellness, Physical Therapy Technician - Arlington, VA December 2016 - April 2018

• Aided Physical Therapists during individualized patient treatment sessions, therapeutic exercises and documentation

EDUCATION

Flatiron School July 2023 - November 2023

Full Stack Web Development | Backend: Python and Flask | Frontend: JavaScript and React

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

August 2012 - May 2016

• Bachelor of Science | Major: Human and Health Sciences